Andrew Rodman lead developer, system architect

I am a vision led project manager who excels at taking customer requirements and turning them into easy to use deliverables. I have experience in the full stack of windows based software-as-a-service world, including but not limited to: database management and design, web-service design, user-interface design, system deployment, IIS configuration and management, domain configuration, email systems, automated reporting systems, security reviews, system documentation, and more. My passion is to deliver front-end experiences that exceed customer and industry expectations.

skills

Project Oversight

Years of experience working with small teams to successfully quickly and effectively accomplish big tasks.

Web Development

SQL Design

Solid understanding of hurdles and solutions at each level in software-as-a-service development, from database to front-end.

Requirement Gathering

Proven history of working with multiple stake holders to define system requirements, supervise development, and deliver products.

+00	\sim 1		\sim
	r 11	111	('
tec			vai

C#/.NET	HTML/CSS	Javascript
JQuery	CVS - SVN/GIT	RESTful Services

experience

VendNovation 2005-Present

SPA Design

System Architect, Project Manager, Developer

M2M Design

Joined the company in its infancy and grew with it, overseeing front-end interface design, database design, project definition, system architecture, system migrations, PCI certification, and much more.

Seattle Pacific University

2001-2005

Information Technology Services

Provided technical support and training for students and staff on a variety of platforms. Assisted professors in preparation of class materials including audio recording and editing of online lectures. Provided image clean-up services for academic publishing.

Logos Research Systems

1998-2001

Electronic Text Developer

Responsible for maintaining on-site archives. Scanned and converted documents to custom text formats using custom perl scripts. Proofread documents to ensure conversion accuracy.

projects

Windows Services

C#, Windows Server

Develope and maintain scalable automated delivery systems for reporting, real-time alert routing, and system health monitoring.

Mobile Interfaces

C#, HTML, JavaScript, JQuery

Built custom, touch based mobile inventory management interfaces including unique controls for value adjustments to maximize customer productivity.

Database Design

SQL Server, C#

Co-designed database structures for multiple real-time transaction based machine-to-machine inventory tracking and access control systems. Implemented SQL to C# object generator that provided data validation and CRUD actions based on SQL schemas

User Interface Design

HTML, CSS, Javascript, C#

Responsible for look and feel as well as usability of several customer facing as well as internal platforms. Co-developed custom controls for quickly selecting hierarchical data sets. Developed custom JavaScript UI framework for supporting in house script service frontends.

Migration to Cloud Services

AWS, Server 2012, SQL Server

Oversaw migration from bare-metal to cloud based hosting on AWS including SQL Server data migration and deployment of IIS hosted websites.

System Integrations

C#, SOAP, REST, Ruby

Designed and implemented multiple specialized third-party integrations, working with remote teams to define system operations and test implementations.

Office Systems Support

Microsoft Server, Cisco Device

Maintain office network security by configuring Cisco Firewall rules, maintaining domain configurations, managing user accounts and security settings, etc.

Seattle Pacific University

2001-2005

BS Computer Science

education